

585 Purdue Mall ME3171, West Lafayette, IN 47907

🗷 hgchi@purdue.edu | 🄏 hyung-gun.me | 🞧 stnoah1 | 🛅 hyung-gun | 🎓 Hyung-gun Chi

# Research Interests

My research interests are primarily focused on the intersection of Computer Vision and Machine Learning, with a particular emphasis on Representation Learning for human actions, 3D Computer Vision, and their practical applications. I aim to explore the development and integration of advanced algorithms for human action recognition, 3D scene understanding, and object detection, specifically for use in Virtual Reality (VR) / Augmented Reality (AR) devices and Autonomous Vehicles.

# **Education**

**Purdue University** West Lafayette, IN, USA

PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2023 (Expected)

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2022

- Thesis: Advancements in Human Action Recognition by Learning Human Skeleton Representations
- · Advisor: Prof. Karthik Ramani

**Purdue University** West Lafayette, IN, USA

MS IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

· Advisor: Prof. Karthik Ramani

**Yonsei University** Seoul, South Korea

BS IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2017

- · Advisor: Prof. Soo-hong Lee
- 2-year military service (2011-2013)

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Toyota Research Institute** Los Altos, CA, USA

RESEARCH INTERN May. 2023 - Aug. 2023

• Conducted human-robot interaction research (Host: Dr. Thomas Kollar).

#### **Honda Research Institute US** San Jose, CA, USA

RESEARCH INTERN

Jan. 2023 - May. 2023

· Conducted human motion prediction research for autonomous vehicles (Host: Dr. Kwonjoon Lee).

**Honda Research Institute US** San Jose, CA, USA

RESEARCH INTERN May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

· Conducted research on future action forcasting task for autonomous vehicles (Host: Dr. Chiho Choi).

**Convergence Design Lab, Purdue University** West Lafayette, IN, USA GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT Aug. 2018 - Present

· Conducted skeleton-based human action recognition and pose estimation research (Advisor: Prof. Karthik Ramani).

**HeumLabs Corporation** Seoul, South Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & CEO

Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2017

- Founded and managed a start-up company as a CEO.
- Developed an office automation system specifically for automating office works.

# **Knowledge-based Design Lab, Yonsie University**

Seoul, South Korea

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

• Participated on the 3D computuer vision research (Advisor: Prof. Soo-Hong Lee).

# **Publications and Patents**

# **Journal Papers**

- [J4] H. Lee, J. Lee, S. Kwon, K. Ramani, H. Chi, and D. Mun. 3D CAD Model Simplification for Mechanical Parts Using Generative Adversarial Networks. In Computer-Aided Design, under revision.
- [J3] S. Kim, H. Chi and K. Ramani. Object synthesis by learning part geometry with surface and volumetric representations. In Computer-Aided Design (2021): 102932.
- [J2] S. Kim, N. Winovich, H. Chi, G. Lin, and K. Ramani. Latent transformations neural network for object view synthesis. In The Visual Computer (2019): 1-15.
- [J1] H. Hwang, S. Lee, H. Chi, N. Kang, H. Kong, J. Lu, and H. Ohk. An Evaluation Methodology for 3D Deep Neural Network using Visualization in 3D Data Classification. In Journal of Mechanical Science and Technology 33, no. 3 (2019): 1333-1339.

## **Conference Proceedings**

- [C9] W. Roh, S. Lee, W. Ryoo, G. Oh, J. Lee, S. Hwang, H. Chi, and S. Kim. Functional Hand Type Prior for 3D Hand Pose Estimation & Action Recognition from Egocentric View Monocular Videos, British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2023. Submitted.
- [C8] H. Chi, S. Chi, Q. Huang, and K. Ramani. Skeleton-ODE: Learning Representation by Predicting the Future for Online Skeletonbased Action Recognition, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023. Submitted.
- [C7] S. Kim, S. Seo, H. Chi, K. Ramani, J. Kim, and S. Kim. Higher-order Relation Reasoning for Trajectory Prediction, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023. Submitted.
- [C6] H. Chi, K. Lee, N. Agarwal, K. Ramani, and C. Choi. AdamsFormer for Spatial Action Localization in the Future, In proceedings of Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023.
- [C5] Y. Xu, A. Bazarjani, H. Chi, C. Choi, and Y. Fu. Uncovering the Missing Pattern: Unified Framework Towards Trajectory Imputation and Prediction, In proceedings of Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023.
- [C4] H. Chi\*, S. Chi\*, S. Chan, and K. Ramani. Pose Relation Transformer: Refine Occlusions for Human Pose Estimation, In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2023.
- [C3] H. Chi\*, M. Ha\*, S. Chi, S. Lee, Q. Huang, and K. Ramani. InfoGCN: Representation Learning for Human Skeleton-based Action Recognition, In proceedings of Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022.
- [C2] H. Chi\*, S. Kim\*, X. Hu, Q. Huang, and K. Ramani. A Large-scale Annotated Mechanical Components Benchmark for Classification and Retrieval Tasks with Deep Neural Networks, In proceedings of European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020.
- [C1] S. Kim, H. Chi, X. Hu, A. Vegesana, and K. Ramani. First-Person View Hand Segmentation of Multi-Modal Hand Activity Video Dataset, In proceedings of British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2020.

### **Preprinted papers**

• S. Kim, J. Bae, H. Chi, S. Hong, B.S. Koh, and K. Ramani. Egocentric View Hand Action Recognition by Leveraging Hand Surface and Hand Grasp Type. arXiv preprint arXiv:2109.03783, 2021.

- [P5] H. Chi, K. Lee, Y. Xu, and C. Choi. System and Method for Providing Spatio-Temporal Action Localization in the Future. US Patent Application.
- [P4] Y. Xu, A. Bazarjani, H. Chi, and C. Choi. Trajectory Imputation and Prediction, US Patent Application.
- [P3] K. Ramani, H. Chi, and S. Chi. Pose Relation Transformer Refine Occlusions for Human Pose Estimation. US Patent Application.
- [P2] K. Ramani, S. Kim, and H. Chi. Pixel-wise Hand Segmentation of Multi-modal Hand Activity Video Dataset. US Patent 11,562,489
- [P1] H. Chi. Computer Input System for Office/Factory Automation. WO Patent 2018/074729 Al.

# Academic Services\_

### **Conference Reviewers**

- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023
- The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023
- The IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023
- The British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC) 2020 2023
- The IEEE Conference on Artificial Intelligence (CAI) 2023

## **Journal Reviewers**

- Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation (JVCI)
- Journal of Computing and Information Science in Engineering (JCISE)
- Computer Vision and Image Understanding (CVIU)

# Invited Talks

#### **Sungkyunkwan University** Seoul, South Korea

Guest Lecturer: Advancements in Human Action Recognition by Learning Skeleton Representations May. 2023

**Keimyung University** Deagu, South Korea

Guest Lecturer: Representations Learning for Recognizing Human Activity Apr. 2023

**Yonsei University** Seoul, South Korea

Guest Lecturer: Representation for Human Activities Apr. 2023

**Hongik University** Seoul, South Korea

Guest Lecturer: Learning Representation for Human Action Recognition Dec. 2022

CDE Challenge - Computational Design and Engineering Tools Section

## Awards and Honors

2022	Travel Grants, Purdue Graduate Student Government	West Lafayette, IN, USA
2016	KISTI (Korea Institute of Science and Technology Information) President's Award,	Seoul, South Korea

2016 Edison Challenge - Computer Aided Design Section CDE (Korea Society for Computational Design and Engineering) President's Award, 2016

Daejeon, South Korea

HYUNG-GUN CHI · CURRICULUM VITAE MAY 22, 2023

**Skills** 

**Research and Development Stacks** 

Major Languages Python, C/C++

Machine LearningPyTorch, TensorFlow, KerasWeb FrameworksDjango, Flask, Node.jsComputer VisionOpenCV, OpenGL

**Web Languages** Nginx, React, HTML5, PHP, JavaScript, CSS

**Database** MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB

**Other Tools and Skills** 

**Text Editors** Neovim & Vim

Other Langauges Shell Scripts(bszh, zsh), Matlab(Octave), R
Operating Systems macOS, Linux Debian/Ubuntu, Windows

IDE VSCode, Eclipse, IDEA

chiho1.choi@samsung.com

**Softwares** SolidWorks, Catia, AutoCAD

VCS Git

**References** 

Karthik RamaniProfessor, Purdue Universityramani@purdue.eduSoo-Hong LeeProfessor, Yonsei Universityshlee@yonsei.ac.kr

**Chiho Choi** Senior Staff Engineer, Samsung Semiconductor USA